Guide to the Lawrence F. Evans Collection, 1978-1988 AIS.1988.17
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lawrence F. Evans Collection
1978-1988
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Evans, Lawrence F.
AIS.1988.17
13.75 Linear Feet (11 boxes and 81 videocassettes)
Biography
Lawrence F. Evans was a steelworker and journalist in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. He was best known for his magazine, The Mill Hunk Herald, which he published from his home. The Mill Hunk Herald included stories, poetry, and editorials regarding the lives of working class men and women, as well as the deindustrialization of Pittsburgh. Evans used the popularity of his magazine to hold fundraisers for unemployed steel mill workers and appeared in two documentaries by filmmaker Tony Buba which portrayed life in the Rust Belt. As The Mill Hunk Herald began to decline in readership, Evans started the Northside Chronicle. The Chronicle featured submissions by local writers and poets and was concerned with community issues and preserving the culture of old Allegheny City, now the North Side of Pittsburgh. Evans left the Chronicle to pursue an oral history project comparing steelworkers and miners in Pittsburgh and its sister city, Donetsk, in Soviet Ukraine. He also conducted many other interviews in Pittsburgh that comprised a series called "Steel Valley Stories" which documented life in Pittsburgh during the 1980s.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lawrence F. Evans on September 1, 1988. Additions to the collection were made in 1989.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Lawrence F. Evans Collection, 1978-1988, AIS.1988.17, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Previous Citation
This collection was previously cited as: Lawrence F. Evans Labor Films and Periodicals, UE/Lab 88:17
Arrangement
Series I. Periodicals.
Series II. Clippings and Correspondence, 1981-1985.
Series III. Publications.
Series IV. Film.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains several films that include oral history interviews of workers from Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Tapes also include footage of labor related activities, and Pittsburgh Community Television shows such as "Steel Valley Stories" and "Our Own Show." Also present are periodicals regarding filmmaking, labor issues, union publications, and the arts. Clippings regarding the Pittsburgh steel industry decline are also present.
Donet︠s︡ʹk (Ukraine); Labor movement -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Periodicals; Working class -- Periodicals; Labor movement -- Periodicals; Labor -- Periodicals; Deindustrialization -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh Region; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Videocassettes; Correspondence; Working class -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Underground press publications -- United Sates; Working class writings, American -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Oral histories (Document genres); Clippings (Information artifacts); Labor; Evans, Lawrence F.
- Periodicals, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series includes periodicals from across the country. Topics include labor issues, working class literature, and filmmaking. Also present are local union newspapers, national union newspapers and magazines by US Steel.
  - Access Video by Access Video of Western PA, Inc., 1984, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Action Bulletin by Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Waste, Inc., 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advance by Trade Union Action League, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AFSC Quaker Service Bulletin by the American Friends Service Committee, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Against the Current by Workers Power, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Allegheny Sierran by the Allegheny Group, Pittsburgh Chapter of the Sierra Club, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allegheny Socialist by New American Movement, Pittsburgh Chapter, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - All Hands Round by Calliope House, Inc., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alternative Media by Alternative Press Syndicate, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alternative Press Syndicate Advertising and Membership Directory, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alternative Press Index by Alternative Press Center, Inc., 1982, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Labor by American Labor Education Center, Inc., 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Writer by the National Writers Union, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Anti-Draft by the Committee Against Registration and the Draft, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Appeal to Reason by Movement Against Racism and the Klan (M.A.R.K.), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Areas of Concern by Harry Hyde, Jr., 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Art Meets Labor, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Association for the Rights of Catholics in the Church (ARCC), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bayou La Rose by Working Class of Ecological Anarchism, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Beef by Pakka K. Kavan, Marina Racine, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Beef Tabloid by Omaha Magic Theatre, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Big Flame, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Black and Green by Rhode Island Alternative Press, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bloomfield Garfield Bulletin by Bloomfield-Garfield Corporation, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Broadside by Broadside, Ltd., 1983, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Building Blocks by National Center for Urban Ethnic Affairs, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - CACOSH Health and Safety News by CACOSH, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Center for Peace Education by Center for Peace Education/Cincinnati Coalition for Peace Education, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Center for Rural Affairs, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Central America Alert by US Out of Central America, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Central American Focus by Central America Mobilization Coalition, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Chapter Voice by the Allegheny Chapter, PSSU, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Chryme by Richard Paul Howe, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Cineaste by Gary Gowdus, 1973, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Citizen Power by Citizen/Labor Energy Coalition, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Civil Disobedience by Groupe Thoreau, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - The Closest Penguins, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Coal Field Defender by United Mine Workers of America, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Coalition Close-Up by Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Columbus Free Press, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Come Unity, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Common Cause, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Community Muralist's Magazine by International Murals Network, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Community Television Review by National Federation of Local Cable Programmers, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Communitas by Center Peace Publishers, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Community News, 1983, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Comparable Worth Project Newsletter, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conscience and Military Tax Campaign, US Newsletter, 1982, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Consumer-Farmer Cooperator by Consumer-Farmer Foundation, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Conversion Planner by SANE, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Convoy Dispatch by Teamsters for a Democratic Union, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Counter Spy, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CPJ Update by Committee to Protect Journalism, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Crazy Horse Spirit by El Centro de la Raza, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CTW Reports by Center for Third World Organizing, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cultural Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dayton Solidarity Press, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The DC Gazette, 1980, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Delaware Alternative Press, 1982, 1984, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Democratic Communique by Union for Democratic Communications, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Democratic Left by The Democratic Socialists of America, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Disorientation Manual by New Indicator Collective Alternative Press Syndicate, 1980, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Dollars & Sense by Economic Affairs Bureau, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Don Bell Reports, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Earthbank News by Earthbank Association, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - East End Cooperative Ministry, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Economic Notes by Labor Research Association, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Emancipation by Anarchist Association of the Americas, 1982, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - EPI Perspectives by Environmental Policy Institute, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Everyone's Backyard by Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes Inc., 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Exchange by Generations Together, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exploring the Bible by Discovery, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - '09 Express by United Steelworkers of America Local 2609, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Far East Reporter by Maude Russell, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Farmer's Legal Action Report by Farmer's Legal Action Group, Inc., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Federation for Progress, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Fessenden Review by The Reginald A. Fessenden Educational Fund Incorporated, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fighting Back by All People's Congress People's Anti-war Mobilization, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Flotsam & Jetsam by DC Gazette, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Focus by World Wildlife Fund, US, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Food Bank Ledger by Pittsburgh Community Food Bank, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Food News and Views by Hunger Action Coalition, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Foreclosure Alert by Center for Community Change, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Francisco E. Martinez Defense Committee, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Freedom Socialist by Freedom Socialist Party, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Free For All by Better World Educational Corporation, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Free Venice Beachhead, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Freeze Challenger by The Pennsylvania Campaign for a Nuclear Weapons Freeze, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Full Moon by Alaska Solidarity Federation, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Global Link Newsletter by The Society of Prayer for World Peace, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Grandfalloon Newsletter by John E. Milich (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Grassroots by Grassroots Leadership, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Guatemala by Guatemala News and Information Bureau, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The Hammer by Institute for Research and Education on Human Rights, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Hard Row to Hoe by Seven Buffaloes Press, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Heathen Science Monitor by Heathen Science Monitor Publications, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Heretic's Journal, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Heretic's Journal Bulletin by Ron Heresy, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - The Hispanic Monitor by Hispanic Monitor/Observador Hispano Inc., 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Hotline by Group Against Smog and Pollution, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - I Can't Explain by Trouble After School Publications, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ideas & Action by Worker's Solidarity Alliance, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - IECON Newsletter by The Interreligious Economic Crisis Organizing Network, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - In Context by Context Foundation, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Industrial Worker by Industrial Workers of the World, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - The Informer by Homewood-Brushton Revitalization and Development Corporation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - In Public Service by AFL-CIO Public Employee Department, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Inside Joke by American Samizdat Press, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - The Insurgent Sociologist by University of Oregon, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Interchange Report by Interchange, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - International Labor Reports by Mayday Publications, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Iron Clad Rag by The Iron Clad Agreement (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Italy and US by Committee for a Democratic Policy Towards Italy, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Jericho by National Moratorium on Prison Construction, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Judgement by Alderson Hospitality House, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ka Huliau by Hawaii Education for Social Progress, Inc., 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Katuah, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Kindred Spirits Journal by Kindred Spirits Journal, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Know News by Know, Inc., 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Labor Clips by SANE, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Labor Notes by Labor Education and Research Project, 1979, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Labor Page by CommUnity News Publishers, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Labor Today by National Center for Trade Union Action and Democracy, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Land & Liberty by Land & Liberty Press, Inc., 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Lifelines by OCAW Union News, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Links12 by NWTUAA Liaison Committee, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Lip by Lancaster Independent Press, Inc., 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Little Free Press, 1976, 1982, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - MediActive by Alternative Media Information Center, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Media Network Newsletter by Alternative Media Information Center, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - MEP News by Marxist Educational Press, 1984, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - The Metro by Scranton Public Theatre, Inc., 1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - The Metro Times, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - MCLR Work by Midwest Center for Labor Research, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - The Militant, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - The Mining Organizer by Center for Alternative Mining Development Policy, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Missouri Valley Socialist by National Committee of the Socialist Party USA, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Modern Times by Hawaii Union of Socialists, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - The Monitor by Friends of ACE, Inc., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - The Monitor by Center for Democratic Renewal, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Moody Street Irregulars, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Motheroot Journal by Motheroot Publications, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - National Action Guide by DC Gazette, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The National Boycott Newsletter, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - National Network for Direct Action by Disarmament Program Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - National NOW Times by National Organization for Women, Inc., 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - National Unemployed News by National Unemployed Network, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Native Communicator by Native Americans in Communication, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Neighborhoods for Living Center News by Urban Redevelopment Authority; ACTION Housing Inc., 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Neighborhood Works by Center for Neighborhood Technology, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The New Abolitionist by Nuclear Free America, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New American Movement, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New Directions for Women by New Directions for Women, Inc., 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The New Humanist by Proutist Universal of North America, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - New Indicator by UCSD, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - New Iron Column by Creative Anarchists Network, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The New People by The Thomas Merton Center, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - News by Pittsburgh Planned Parenthood, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1199 News by National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - News from the Film Fund by The Film Fund, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Newsletter of the Center for Business, Society & Ethics, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Newsletter by Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Newsletter by National Anti-Klan Network, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter by National Murals Network, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Newsletter by Pittsburgh Men's Collective, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Newsletter by Pittsburgh Neighborhood Alliance, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Newsletter by Swords into Plowshares, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Newsletter by Tri-State Conference on Steel, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Newsletter by Western Review Institute, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - News & Notes by Union for Democratic Communications, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - New Unionist by The New Unionists, 1980-1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The New York Alliance by New Alliance Party, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Night Times by College of General Studies Student Government, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Nonviolent Anarchist Newsletter by Nonviolent Anarchist Network (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - North American Farmer by North American Farm Alliance, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Northern Neighbors by Northern Neighbors Ltd., 1984, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Northwest Passage by Northwest Passage, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Nuclear Free Press, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - The Occasional Review by Realities Library (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Okanogan Natural News by G. Payton and R. Gillespie, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - On Guard by Citizen Soldier, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - On Watch by National Lawyers Guild Military Law Task Force, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Open Road, 1982-1984, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Organizing Notes by Campaign for Political Rights, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Our Right to Know by Fund for Open Information and Accountability, Inc., 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Our Socialism by OS Publications, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Overthrow by Youth International Party Information Service, 1979-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ozarkia by EcoCenter Inc., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - PAAR Spective by Pittsburgh Action Against Rape, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pangloss Papers by Pangloss Foundation, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PED Forum by AFL-CIO Public Employee Department, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania Times by National Organization for Women, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The People by Socialist Labor Party, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - People's Medical Society Newsletter by People's Medical Society, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The People's Voice, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - People's Tribune, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Philippine Labor Alert by Philippine Workers Support Committee, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Pikestaff Forum by Pikestaff Publications, Inc., 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Pittsburgh Arts by Pittsburgh-Allegheny County Cultural Alliance, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Pittsburgh Federalist by World Federalist Association of Pittsburgh, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Pittsburgh Woman, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Plain Speaking by Democratic Workers Party, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Pledge of Resistance Newsletter, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Plowshare Press by Center for Economic Conversion, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Plumbing the Depths of the Nuclean Neurosis by Duncan & Porter House (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Point Blank (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Pop News by People Organizing People, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Post Amerikan, 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
  - The Power Line by Environmental Action Foundation, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Prarie Rambler, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Processed World, 1981-1983, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Program on Workers Culture by Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Process, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Progressive by The Progressive, Inc., 1979, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Prout News by Prout Universal, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - PSN News by Progressive Student Network, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Public Eye by Citizens in Defense of Civil Liberties, 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Public Interest News by Pennsylvania Public Interest Coalition, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Public Interest Video Network by USER,Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Public News by Pennsylvania Humanities Council, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Racine Labor by Union Labor Publishing Company, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Radical Historians Newsletter by MARHO, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Radical Perspectives on the Economic Crisis of Monopoly Capitalism by The Union for Radical Political Economics; A Political Education and Action Potential, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Railroad Notes by Labor Research Association, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Rank & File News by Rank & File Coalition (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Rank & File Steelworkers Voice by USWA District 1, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Rebel Worker, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - RECON by RECON Publications, 1976, 1982-1984, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Red Bass by Anti-Media, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Regeneration by Rodale Press, Inc., 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Relay by Labor Institute of Public Affairs, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Reporter by Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Resistance by Friends of Durruti, Open Road, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Resource Center Bulletin by the Resource Center, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Road Report by Southern Appalachian Labor School, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Rodo Joho, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Rosewood by Women's Center and Shelter of Greater Pittsburgh, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Saboteur by Pajaro Press, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Science, Class & Politics by Marxist-Leninist League, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Shelterforce by National Housing Institute, 1980-1986 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Sipapu by Noel Peattie, 1981-1986 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Small Farm Advocate, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Socialist Worker by International Socialist Organization, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Solidarity by International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agriculture Implement Workers of America, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Solidarity International Newsletter by Solidarity International Inc., 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Solidarity Works, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Songsmith Journal by Songsmith Society, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Southeast Asia Chronicle by Southeast Asia Resource Center, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Southern Advocate by Equal Rights Congress, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Southern Changes by Southern Regional Council, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Southern Fight-Back by Southern Organizing Committee for Economic and Social Justice, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Southern Libertarian Messenger, 1980, 1982-1984, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Southern Neighborhoods by Community Control Movement in the South, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Spare Change (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Speaking Out, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Steelworker by USWA Local 1010, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The Steelworkers Oldtimer, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Strike, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Striking Back, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Survival Network Newsletter by Leonard Peltier Support Group (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Sylvanian by Pennsylvania Chapter of Sierra Club, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Synthesis by University Women's Center, University of Pittsburgh, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Synthesis by League for Ecological Democracy, 1982, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Tabloid by SMC Local 7027, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Talkin' Union, 1982, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Tennessee Woolen Worker by Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - The Texas Observer by Texas Observer Publishing Co., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Theaterwork by Cherry-Creek Inc., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Third Force by The Center for Third World Organizing, 1983, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Toronto-Clarion by Western Gap Communications Cooperation Limited, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 29)